Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Commercially Released Media, 267138
  - Subseries B: Video recordings, 267141
    - Sylvia Safdie: "Reflections: A Trilogy (demo)", 2007- 2009; 267201 (Box 38)
      Duration: 14 minutes
    - "Vertiges" Fortier Danse-Creation, 2012; 267202 (Box 38)
  - Subseries C: Vinyl Sound Discs, 267146
    Subseries C is comprised of commerically released vinyl sound discs.
    - "Early Electronic/ Tape Collage Music"; Alga Marghen, 2008; 267203 (Box 39)
      Contents: Sheep meadow (6:34) -- Images of Cheng Hsieh (15:51) -- It seemed to me (5:42) -- Judson #6 piece (6:43) -- Illuminations from Fantastic gardens: for vocal ensemble / text, Arthur Rimbaud (13:03).
      Original format: (1 sound disc) analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo.; 12 in.
    - "Full Circle Sounding" Malcolm Goldstein; Kye, 2015; 276313 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "Musical Elements 10th Anniverrsary Recording"; CRI, 1987; 267204 (Box 39)
      Contents: Passage I / Wyner (8:48) -- A breaking of vessels, becoming song / Goldstein (15:10) -- Fantasy etudes / Lerdahl (14:08). Credits: Musical Elements; Robert Dick, solo flute (2nd work); Daniel Asia (1st-2nd works) and Robert Beaser (3rd work), conductors.
    - "One Hundred Years of Soundings" Philip Corner and Malcolm Goldstein; Alga Marghen, 1998; 267214 (Box 39)
      LP 1: Side One: Tongues og my Mother's Teaching (20'12") LP 1: Side Two: (gamelon) Antipode (12'00); Configurations in Darkness (07'36") LP 2: Side Three: An Enactment of Absence (18'36") LP2: Side Four: [Untitled: Malcolm was guest in Philip's loft at 75 Leonard St. in New York City where they played together on December 1, 1991] (21'15")
      Original format: (2 sound discs) analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo.; 12 in.
    - "Organic Oboe" Joseph Celli; Stereo O. O. Records, 1979; 267215 (Box 39)
      Contents: Sky:S for J: for five English horns (without reeds)(1976) / Joseph Celli. -- Spiral: for soloist (1968) / Karlheinz Stockhausen. -- Extended oboe: for oboe & electronic tape (1973-74) / Elliott Schwartz. -- A summoning of focus: for wind instrument (1977) / Malcolm Goldstein. Credits: Joseph Celli (live and taped oboe, English horns, voice, and other sounds and modifiers).
    - "The Seasons: Vermont for Magnetic Tape Collage & Instrumental Ensemble" Malcolm Goldstein; Folkways Records, 1983; 267217 (Box 39)
      Contents: Summer (14:50) -- Autumn (10:15) -- Winter (19:40) -- Springs (5:00). Credits: Performed by various musicians with various instruments.
    - "Soundings for solo violin" Malcolm Goldstein; Real Art Ways, 1980; 267218 (Box 39)
      Credits: Improvisations performed by Malcolm Goldstein.
    - "Vision Soundings" Malcolm Goldstein; Malcolm Goldstein, 1985; 267219 (Box 39)
      Contents: From center of rainbow, sounding: violin solo (18:20) -- Vision tree fragment: maple tree limb and vocal solo (17:20).
    - "The Winds Rise in the North" Harlen Gaber; Titanic, 1976; 267220 (Box 39)
      Ensemble: Violin: Linda Cummiskey, Malcolm Goldstein, Hathy Seplow; Viola: Stephen Reynolds; Cello: David Gibson
- Series VI: Non-commercially Released Audio, 267139
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  Series VI comprises non-commercially released audiocassetes and sound discs. It is split into two subseries containing performances and interviews. Each subseries is described more fully below.
  - Subseries A: Performances, 267144
    Subseries A is comprised of non-commercially released audiocassettes, sound discs, and one reel. More information about the known contents of each media item is listed below.
    Materials are arranged alphabetically by title as designated on the object.
    Material is currently unavailable. Please contact Fales Library for further information.
    - Acoustic Art (Horspiel) Works, September 26, 1985; February 18, 1988; April 22, 1998; ID: 350.0001; 267310 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0001)
      1) "The Edges of Sound WIthin" (19'55") 2) "Ishi/time changing spaces" (19'54") 3) "as it were, another" (21'08") Westdeutscher Rundfunk Cologne, Studip Akustische Kunst
      Original format: 1 sound disc: digital; 4 3/4 in.
    - Acoustic Art (Horspiel) Radio, 1993- 1997; ID: 350.0002; 267331 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0002)
      1) "Between (two) spaces" (37'55") Westdeutscher Rundfunk, Cologne. Studio Akustische Kunst 2) "Regarding the Tower of Babel" (25'10") Hessischer Rundfunk Ensemble fur Neue Musik. Premier: TheaterHaus Frankfurt
    - "As it were, another" Studio Akustische Kunst, WDR Koln, 1996- 1998; ID: 350.0003; 267332 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0003)
      "As it were, another" (1998) radio/acoustic art. "As it were" (1996) Malcolm Goldstein: Violin. Robert Black: Cello. Charles Wood: Percussion. World premier Merkin Concert. "Gentle rain preceeding mushrooms (in memorium John Cage)"
    - "As it were, another" Studio Akustische Kunst, WDR Koln, April 22, 1998; ID: 350.0004; 267222 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0004)
      Benedikt Bitzendorfer, tonmeister (21,08")
      Original format: 1/4" audiocassette
    - "Barre Phillips and Malcolm Goldstein: Black Bot Munster", October 4, 2009; ID: 350.0005; 267384 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0005)
    - "Barre Phillips and Malcolm Goldstein: Live at Montevideo, Marseille", April 8, 2006; ID: 350.0006; 267383 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0006)
    - "Barre Phillips and Malcolm Goldstein: Wels Concert", October 6, 2009; ID: 350.0007; 267385 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0007)
      1) Intro W.W. (0'30"); 2)"On a Tuesday Evening" (20'15"); 3)"Just like real musicians" (9'08"); 4)"That's our favourite key" (8'54"); 5)"It's my speciality these days" (11'18"); 6)"Kleines Stuck ohne Titel" (7'40").
    - "Beginning articulations" part I of "On the edge of song", Music Gallery, Toronto, May 28, 2011; ID: 350.0008; 267333 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0008)
      Eve Egoyan, pianist. Premier (17'00")
    - "Bimhuis, Amsterdam: October Meeting 1991", ID: 350.0009; 267223 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0009)
      George Lewis, Trombone Anthony Braxton, saxophone Evan Parker, saxophone Malcolm Goldstein, violin Bernard Mixon, voice
    - "Bimhuis, Amsterdam: Solo Violin", November 5, 1990; ID: 350.0010; 267224 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0010)
    - Boulder Museum of Contemporary Art Concert Preliminary Mix 1, August 24, 2002; ID: 350.0011; 267334 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0011)
      1. Malcolm Intro (2:26) 2. Malcolm Intro Complete (2:52) 3.Configurations (10:24) 4.Speak Intro (0:41) 5.Gentle Rain (10:14) 6. Speak Intro (0:45) 7. Looking Backwards (15:46) 8. Speak Intro (0:46) 9.My feet my soul (9:41) 10.Speak Intro (0:46) 11. Improvised Encore (2:45) 12. Ken Thanks (0:33).
    - "A Breaking of Vessels, Becoming Song" Musical Elements premier, undated; ID: 350.0012; 267225 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0012)
      Robert Dick solo flute
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" Brooklyn Philharmonic, March 22, 1985; ID: 350.0013; 267226 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0013)
      Lukas Foss, conductor
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" Brooklyn Philharmonic/ Meet the Moderns series, March 22, 1985; ID: 350.0014; 267335 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0014)
      Lukas Foss: Conductor; Malcolm Goldstein: Violin Solo, NYC
    - Chapel Performance Space, Seattle, Washington, November 5, 2011; ID: 350.0015; 267336 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0015)
      Disc 1: 1) From "Fragments of the Wall" 2) "Configurations in darkness" Disc 2: 3) "On and on and always slowly nowhere" 4)"My feet is tired but my soul is rested" 5)"Two silences" 6)"Soundings" Credits: Eric Barber: Saxophones. Stuart Dempster: Trombone. Beth Fleenor: Clarinet and Bass Clarinet. Lori Goldston: Cello. Esther Sugai: Flute. Recorded by Steve Peters.
      Original format: 2 sound discs: digital; 4 3/4 in.
    - "Configurations in darkness" at HERE, NYC, August 10, 1995; ID: 350.0016; 267227 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0016)
      Improvisation on Serbo-Croation folk song. Excerpt from "Configurations in Darkness" NYC- HERE premier.
    - Cornish Institute '86, October 1986; ID: 350.0017; 267230 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0017)
      Side A: Soundings for Solo Violin; The Edges of Sound WIthin; Out of the Corners of My Eyes Side B: Yosha's Mornings Song; Qerneraq; Our Breath as Bones Premier The New Performance Group- Seattle
    - Cornish Institute- New Performance Group, Seattle, February 20, 1994; ID: 350.0018; 267265 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0018)
      Side A) 1. "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (17'00") 2. "...out of changes: Keeping Still; Mountain" (23'30") Side B) 1. "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms (13'00") (with cold in throat!) 2. "that is poetry as" (2'30") 3. "Soweto Stomp" (12'00") with New Performance Group Seattle, WA
    - "Coyote's Breath Over the Water" ("La Souffle du Coyote a la Surface de l'Eau"), January 23, 1996; ID: 350.0019; 267228 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0019)
      Malcolm Goldstein composition, performance, mix (1995-1996) Studio 12 Recording: Yves LePage; Mix: Dennis Freceite; Production: Helene Drevost for Societe Radio-Canada "Le Navire Night"
    - "Coyote's Breath Over the Water" ("La Souffle du Coyote a la Surface de l'Eau") Final Mix Copy, January 23, 1996; ID: 350.0020; 267229 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0020)
      Malcolm Goldstein composition, performance, mix (1995-1996) Studio 12 Recording: Yves LePage; Mix: Dennis Freceite; Production: Helene Drevost Final Mix for performance use
    - "Dacapo Konzart- 200" Goldstein and Kaul, June 12, 1990; ID: 350.0021; 267231 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0021)
    - "Darkness becoming narrative" performed by L'Archipel Nocturne at Musique Action, Vandoeuvre-les-Nancy, France, May 19, 2010; ID: 350.0022; 267337 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0022)
      Recorded by Yannick Herpin. (27'05")
    - DRAM (New World) Radio Program, February, 2011; ID: 350.0023; 267376 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0023)
      (60'48").
    - "The edges of sound within" WDR studio concert and performance, September 28, 1985; ID: 350.0024; 267233 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0024)
      The edges of sound within (19'55") and WDR Concert performance Inspielband (19'48")
    - "Electronic/tape collage music" Judson Dance Theater, 1963, 1966, 1967; ID: 350.0025; 267338 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0025, Case 350.0025)
      1) "It seemed to me" (5'43") 1963, for Arlene Rothlein's dance. 2) "Judson #6 Piece" (6'43") 1963, for Ruth Emerson's dance. 3) "Sheep Meadow" (6'42") 1966, for anti-Vietnam war setting. 4)"Images from Cheng Hsieh" (15'51") 1967, for Carol Marcy's dance; also can be played with "Violence of Small Sounds".
      Original format: (1 sound disc) digital, 4 3/4 in.
      An access CD is available for listening in the reading room.
    - "An enactment of absence" (compilation), 1984, 1995, 1996; ID: 350.0026; 267339 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0026)
      1) "An enactment of absence" (18'52") 1995. 2)"Soundings for solo violin" (11'40"). 3)"as it were" (18'05") December, 1996 with Malcolm Goldstein, Joseph Kubera, Robert Black, Charles Wood at Merkin Concert Hall, NYC. 4)"Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall" (12'42") 1984, Brooklyn Philharmonic, Lukas Foss conductor.
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation, November 21, 1987; ID: 350.0027; 267234 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0027)
      Side One: 1) Soundings (4'15") 2) Edges of Sound Within 3) from "The Life Cycles of Stones" (15'00") premier version Side Two: 1) from "Life Cycles of Stones" (5'00") completed 2) Elegia (se hable espanol) (40'00") first pt. 30 premier with Nancy Guevara
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation, March 20, 1993; ID: 350.0028; 267235 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0028)
      Side A: 1) "Soundings" 16'00 2) "Ishi" Side B: 3) "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms" NYC premier 14'30" 4) "qaumaneq; shaking with joy" world premier 15'30"
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation, March 8, 2005; ID: 350.0029; 267340 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0029)
      1) "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (14'50"). 2)"Harscrabble Songs" (10'07"). 3)"approaching the Wall (Li Po text)" (7'32") premier Li Po Text song as a work in progress. 4)"Where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards?!" (17'40"). 5)"Soundings" (10'52").
    - Exploratorium Berlin, November 1, 2006; ID: 350.0030; 267381 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0030)
      "Fragments of the Wall"; "Where are we going when we're standing still looking backwards?!"; "qerneraq: our breath as bones"; "Hardscrabble Songs (song #4)"; "Soundings"
    - Festival Suoni per il popolo, Montreal, June 3, 2008; ID: 350.0031; 267341 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0031)
      1) "Hardscrabble Songs" (13'05"). 2)"A New Song of many faces for In These Times" (17'52"). Quatuor Bozzini.
    - "Fiddling Cow Bells", June 13, 1988; ID: 350.0032; 267236 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0032)
      "Fiddling Cow Bells" No dynamic changes
    - "Fragments of the Wall" excerpt from performance at Chapelle historique du Bon Pasteur, February 11, 2009; ID: 350.0033; 267342 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0033)
      1) Bosnia-Herzogovinia folk songs and improvisation 2)"Fooling the Killers" poetry of Taha Muhammad Ali 3)"Dance" (13'38"). Recorded by Matthieu Belanger
    - "Fragments of the Wall" premier from Radio France Recording, September 12, 2008; ID: 350.0034; 267343 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0034)
      Ce vaut jamais le reel festival. Instants Chavires, Montreal France. With Maclolm Goldstein: violin, Jim Denley: Saxophone, Thierry Madiot: trombone, Louis-Michael Marion: cb, Matthias Kaul: percussion, Li-Ping Ting:danse.
    - "Fragments of the Wall", undated; ID: 350.0163; 267692 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0163)
      "Images of Cheng Hsieh" (15'51"); "Fooling the Killers" Taha Muhammad Ali reading (2'00")
      Original format: (1 sound disc ) digital; 4 3/4 in.
    - "Free at Last" #1, January 16, 1986; ID: 350.0035; 267237 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0035)
      A) Been in the storm so long B) Funeral- Archie Shepp, Soweto Stomp- Malcolm Goldstein Northweatern University, Boston. (Dolby).
    - "Free at Last" #2, January 16, 1986; ID: 350.0036; 267238 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0036)
      A) "My feet is tired, but my sould is rested"- Malcolm Goldstein B) "...that hung like fire on heaven" Malcolm Goldstein (23'15")
    - "Fylkingen", April 10, 1984; ID: 350.0037; 267239 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0037)
      1) Soundings, entrance 2) jade mountain soundings (13'00") 3) from center of rainbow soungings RR recording engineer: Rone Sundvall
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending", April 10, 1981; ID: 350.0038; 267240 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0038)
      premier Macalester College flute ensemble (20'20")
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending", April 10, 1981; ID: 350.0039; 267344 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0039)
      Premier Macalester College flute ensemble (20'58")
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending", April 1981; ID: 350.0040; 267394 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0040)
      Flute Ensemble recorded at Macalester College
      Original format: 7 1/2 IPS stereo copy
    - "Illuminations..." and other pieces from the early 1960's, ID: 350.0041; 267241 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0041)
      Side A: 1) Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens a) Dolby C b) No Dolby (missing beginning) Side B: 1) Ludlow Blues (wind instrument and electronic tape) 2) Emanations (violin and cello) 3) Stillpoint (brass quintet) 4) Paradoxes (violin, trumpet, bassoon, vocal. All taped from single LP made in the '60s tapes in Vermont (scratchy)
    - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens", April 24, 1964; ID: 350.0042; 267345 (Box 43, Media ID: 350.0042)
      Tone Roads concert, New School for Social Research NYC (first concert performance). Vocalists: Beth Cuje, Norma Marder, Robert Ramieri and John Wilson. (12'55").
    - "Images from Cheng Hsieh" and "Violence of Small Sounds", undated; ID: 350.0043; 267242 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0043)
      Stereo Tape Collage (performance tape copy)
    - "Improvisation: Goldstein with Philip Corner" NYC, November 14, 1991; December 1, 1991; ID: 350.0044; 267590 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0044)
      With Laura Donnelly dancing and Phoebe Neville dancing.
    - "Interlude(s)" Universite Bishop's Radio Canada., 2000, 2001; ID: 350.0045; 267346 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0045)
      2) S. Ferguson "Preperation" 3) M. Goldstein "Interlude(s)" (7'35") 4) O.Larue "Poussierres" 5) J.F. Laporte "L'Invisible piano"
    - "Ishi/time changing spaces" WDR horspiel, February 18, 1988; ID: 350.0046; 267245 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0046)
      Westdeutscher Rundfunk Koln Horspiel/Studio Master Tape
    - "Jade Mountain Soundings", October 17, 1995; ID: 350.0047; 267246 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0047)
      Technician: Yves LePage Realization: Helene Premt Studio 12 Pour "Le Navine Night", 13 minutes
    - "Jade Mountain Soundings" DRS (multiple tracks), 1987; ID: 350.0048; 267247 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0048)
      Jade Mountain Soundings (21'45") multiple tracks with live performance at Neve Horizonte Concert Berne (recorded by DRS) Switzerland
    - "John Cage: 'Ryoanji' and 'Score and 23 Parts'", September 19, 1992; ID: 350.0049; 267248 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0049)
      HR Ensemble for New Music- Malcolm Goldstein, director Concert at Anarchic Harmony festival- music of John Cage, Frankfurt
    - Klangforum Wien: Konzerthaus Wien/ Mozart saal, April 6, 2006; ID: 350.0050; 267347 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0050)
      1) "A cultivation of field" (12'00") 2)"What can be said of our differences?" (18'50")
    - Klangforum Wien: Musik Triennale Koln, April 29, 2007; ID: 350.0051; 267348 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0051)
      1) "A cultivation of field" (13'40") 2)"What can be said of our differences?" (21'32")
    - Klangzeit Munster: Grenzgange fest, Cuba, October 26, 2006; ID: 350.0052; 267349 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0052)
      "Configurations in Darkness"; "My feet is tired but my soul is rested"; "Soundings" (9'44")
    - Knitting Factory, NYC, January 10, 1988; ID: 350.0053; 267249 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0053)
      violin solo: 18'05" and 10'00"
    - Knitting Factory, NYC, November 13, 1988; ID: 350.0054; 267250 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0054)
      Goldstein- solo violin
    - La Sala Rossa, Montreal: solo violin concert, September 29, 2011; ID: 350.0055; 267365 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0055)
      1) Intro talk 2)"Soundings" 3)"Eight Whiskus" John Cage 4)"gentle rain preceding mushrooms" 5)"Sounding the Fragility of Line 6)"Soundings" 7)"on and on and always slowly nowhere"
    - Le Port de Tete, Montreal, November 13, 2011; ID: 350.0056; 267350 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0056)
      1) "Mais une oiseau qui n'est pas chante" from "Fragments of the Wall" (6'15"). 2)"On and on and always slowly nowhere" (23'30") 3)"Soundings" (11'06") 4)"on a journey...wandering still" (7'20"). Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", undated; ID: 350.0057; 267251 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0057)
      collage part (Track I and II) stereo cassette Master
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", June 21, 1989; ID: 350.0058; 267252 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0058)
      from Reel I: loop 5'20"
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", June 21, 1987; ID: 350.0059; 267253 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0059)
      from Reel II: loop c. 7'20"
    - " Liu Fang and Malcolm Goldstein: Duo Improvization", October 4, 2003; ID: 350.0060; 267379 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0060)
      Recorded by Eric Lewis.
    - "Logos/Ghent", March 13, 1989; ID: 350.0061; 267255 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0061)
      Side I: 1) "Ishi/'man waxati' Sounding" (21'00") 2) "Out of the Corners of My Eyes (18'30") Side 2: 1) Sounding the Fragility of Line (16'00") 2) Soundings (19'00")
    - "Ludlow Blues", 1963; ID: 350.0062; 267351 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0062)
      For Flute, Alto Saxophone, Trombone, and Electronic Sounds. (Transferred from Cassette tape recording).
    - "L'usine" Concert solo with Rainer Wiens, March 1996; ID: 350.0063; 267256 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0063)
      A) Duet with Rainer Wiens (23'25") B) Soundings for Solo Violin (20'40") at "L'usine" Montreal
    - "Marin's Lied" WDR Koln- Horspiel, November 1984; ID: 350.0064; 267257 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0064)
      Marin's Lied Illuminiert (29'20")
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated", undated; ID: 350.0065; 267258 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0065)
      Tape Collage Part
    - "Marin's Song Illuminated" (Alternative Museum Performance) with "Vermont Night Song/Soundings", 1981, 1983; ID: 350.0066; 267261 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0066)
      A) Marin's Song, Illuminated (Alternative Museum performance) 1981- edited for radio broadcast B) Vermont Night Song and Soundings (Center of Rainbow Sounding)/ Experimental Intermedia Foundation May 12, 1983 (18'45")
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated: fragments and variations", March 6, 1982; ID: 350.0067; 267259 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0067)
      xx
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated: fragments and variations" at Experimental Intermedia Foundation, April 3, 1981; ID: 350.0068; 267260 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0068)
    - "Matthias Kaul and Malcolm Goldstein Duo: SWR2 Now Jazz Summit" Basel, April 28, 2005; ID: 350.0069; 267387 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0069)
    - "Matthias Kaul and Malcolm Goldstein" Montrevil, France, September 17, 2008; ID: 350.0070; 267378 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0070)
      Radio France Recording: Instants Chavires.
      Currently unavailable.
    - "A meditation/ response to Charles Ives' 'Unanswered Question'" live installation performance at Ellen Gallery, Concordia University, Montreal, November 18, 2006; ID: 350.0071; 267352 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0071)
      Recorded by Mathieu Belanger.
    - "Meditation in Darkness" Alison Knowles, May 2002; ID: 350.0072; 267353 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0072)
      2 Audio Tracks. Track 1) 4:06" Track 2) 3:59"
    - Merkin Concert Hall, NYC: Interpretations concert series, December 4, 1996; ID: 350.0073; 267244 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0073)
      Side A: "an enactment of absence" world premier (1995) [18'52"]; "Sounding for Solo Violin" [11'40"] Side B: "as it were" (1996) [18'05"] Malcolm Goldstein: violin, Joseph Kubera: piano, Robert Black: bass, Charles Wood: percussion
    - Mills College Concert, February 12, 1997; ID: 350.0074; 267262 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0074)
      Side A: 1) from "configurations in darkness" (14'25") 2) "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms" Side B: 1) "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings" (19'05") 2) Soundings (9'00") DAT original at MIlls
    - "Montreal Miniature" and "Art Talks" interview, February and March1997; ID: 350.0075; 267263 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0075)
      1) "Montreal Miniature" for "Montreal Sounds Like" February 19, 1997 CBC Montreal, (5'00") Master Cassette 2) "Art Talks" CBC/AM interview and premier AM radio broadcast March 1, 1997 with Shelley Pomerance
    - "Musik am Sonntagnachmittag XLV" Violin Solo, December 3, 1995; ID: 350.0076; 267264 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0076)
      A) "Ishi/'man waxati'"(18'10"), "gentle rain preceeding mushrooms" (12'30") B) "my feet is tired bit my soul is rested" (18'19"), "Soundings" (11'35"), "Trinity" (Ornette Coleman)
    - Musique Action: Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, May 17, 2002; ID: 350.0077; 267354 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0077)
      "Ishi/'man waxati' Soundings"; "my feet is tired but my soul is rested"(11'20"); "Soundings"(10'36"); "where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards?!" with introduction in French; Short Encore.
    - "A New Song of many faces for In These Times" The Locrian Chamber Players String Quartet, NYC, February 7, 2008; ID: 350.0078; 267356 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0078)
      (18'52").
    - "A New Song of many faces for In These Times" Quatuor Bozzini, Theatre La Chapelle, May 2002; ID: 350.0079; 267357 (Box 42, Media ID: 350.0079)
      Clemens Merkel; Genevieve Beaudry; Stephanie Bozzini; Isabelle Bozzini. Societe Radio Canada Recording.
    - "Of Sky Bright Mushrooms Bursting in My Head" dress rehearsal recording, July 3, 1984; ID: 350.0080; 267266 (Box 41, Media ID: 350.0080)
      New Music America, Hartford used for NPR and Europe distribution (Relache)